# 无尽的... #
# Endless... #
# 无尽翻滚的波涛... #
# Endless rolling waves... #
# 你会带给我什么 #
# What do you carry to me? #
# 你会带我到哪里去 #
# Where will you carry me to? #
# 我镇上的孩子们在沙滩上建沙子城堡 #
# Children building castles in the sand in my town #
# 孩子们... #
# Children... #
# 有一个乐队... #
# A band's playing... #
# 有一个乐队明晚会在镇里表演...他们更酷 #
# A band's playing tomorrow night in my town... They're cooler! #
乐队名是...
The...Soron....
# 女士们都带着孩子... #
# Ladies have babies... #
# 世间都是如此 #
# That's how it works... #
# 穿着红外套的女士 你拿那个包干什么? #
# Lady in the red coat what are you doing with that bag?  #
# 穿着蓝外套的女士 你认识那个穿红外套的吗? #
# Lady in the blue coat do you know the lady in the red coat? #
慢点
Slowly.
小盒子...
Little boxes...
# 小盒子... #
# Little boxes... #
# 带我走... #
# To take me away... #
# 把我从这些小盒子里面... #
# from these little boxes... #
嗨 甜心
Hi, sweetheart.
- 呃 嗨  - 刚给你做好烩菜
- Eh, hi. - Just in time, made you casserole...
- 哦不用了 我正有点灵感写歌... - 今天工作怎么样?
- Oh no thanks, I got an idea for a song... - How's work?
不错 我只是...在我忘掉这之前...
Yes, good. I just...before I forget it...
嗯 一个A小调起音的灵感 拟题为郊区生活
Okay, idea for a song in A minors, possible title Suburbia
# 我梦见有一个天使 # 降到E调做基本音
# I dream of an angel # Down to E in the base.
# 带我走 #
# To take me away #
到G调 # 带我走 # C调
To G. # Take me away # C
# 从小盒子里面 #
# From the little boxes #
回到A调 # 我梦想有一个天使 # 升高到F
Back to A. # I dream of an angel # Up the F.
#带我...# 等等 #走# 哎糟糕...
#To take...# hang on #me away# Oh, fuck...
这首操蛋的歌
This madness...this fucking madness song!
为音乐埋首苦干了一整天
现在吃晚饭去了 #nomnomnom#
听译: 圭声 L.Ling Susie 朝歌 轩轩 長安君 rhico
笔译: 虹哥 長安君 陈低 小妖 Harry Joel rhico
1995年混曲
1997年五十大金曲
1998年五十大金曲
我的最爱
校对: rhico 二骚 長安君 锦年
时间轴: 圭声 rhico
压制: rhico
Jon 别灰心
呃 但并不是乔纳森或者...
Eh, but not Johston or...
所以您如何评价...呃先生您如何评价您的音乐?
So how would you describe the ehh sir...How would you describe your music?
- Fancy谢谢你的提问 - 这真他妈是个无聊的问题
- Thank you for your inquiry, Fancy - That's pretty fucking boring question
呃 难道这不是潮流吗?
Eh, that's the edgy isn't it?
- 我觉得我们的歌超级幸福的... -让他说啊 - 操!
- I would describe our sound as fucking happy... -Let him speak - Fuck you!
- 奶酪火腿三明治?  给你...  - 让他说啊
- Cheese and ham panini? Here you go - Let him speak
奶酪和火腿三明治
Cheese and ham panini
#活在梦里#
#Living the dream
先生 你还好吗
Hello, sir.
你们想干什么...
What are you going to...
我要自杀! 我是认真的!
I'll do it! I mean it!
- 你们他妈的...  - 赶紧上来!
- Are you fucking me... - Get out of the water!
我们在做电台节目
We are at this radio station.
他和Clara闹了点矛盾 或者我该说打了一架
He and Clara had a disagreement. Or, I dunno, I guess a physical fight.
你们是...你们今晚有演出
You are the So... You playing tonight.
怎么演? 我们的键盘手正试着把自己淹死呢
How? Our keyboardist is trying to drown himself.
我也是键盘手
I play keyboards.
- 哦不不不 我不是想...那个我不是想要... - 是吗?
- Oh, no...no! I wasn't...that wasn't... I... - Yeah?
行
Okay
你弹C, F和G调吗?
You played C, F and G?
弹啊
Yeah?
你来吧
You are in.
真的?
Really?
所以我们现在该干什么? 我们要不要排练一遍曲子?
So what should we do now? Should we run though the songs?
今晚9点去后台
Stage door 9 p.m. tonight.
呃...好的...那我给你我的电话号码!
Eh... Okay...Well lemme give you my number!
他还好吗?
Is he gonna be okay?
他会没事的
He will be fine.
但是他晚上还是要在医院过夜的吧?
He will still need spend the night in the hospital right?
他灌了太多海水 可能会出现胃部不适
He swallowed a lot of sea water. It may end up be stomach problems.
有人吗?
Hello?
歌名: Ginger Croutons
- 怎么回事?停下来干嘛?! 你他妈的...
- What happened? Just stop playing... You fucking...
- 你他妈地怎么停下来了 - 你有病啊 - 胡扯!
- Why would you just stop fucking playing? - Bullshit!
- 操蛋! 真他妈的操蛋!
- Bullshit! Just bullshit!
没事儿 来 走吧
It's okay. Come on.
开车
Start up the car.
- 您好? - 嗯...Lucas回不来了所以我们需要一个新的键盘手
- Hello? - So... Lucas has been sectioned and we need a new keyboard player,
然后Frank说...
and Frank said... you know...
记得上周末那个不请自来的漂亮男孩儿吗?
Remember that grateful looking a boy jumped up the stage last weekend uninvited
我哪有不请自来! 喂?
I wasn't uninvited! Hello?
Frank觉得你带来了些珍贵的东西
Frank thought you might brought something cherishable that night
但他在那个头套里说话实在听不清
But he gets down really muffled down in the head
所以我以为他说你带来了什么易腐坏的东西
So I thought he said you brought something perishable
你知道就像一箱子吃的 鱼啊水果啊啥的
You know like foods in the case, like fish or fruit
所以我说得了吧老兄 谁干不了这个啊!
So I said come on man, anybody can do that
不管怎么说了 我们现在要去爱尔兰做些新音乐 你来吗?
So anyways, we are doing this really major thing over in Ireland. You in?
- 当然! - 好 M25公路克拉克肯特港服务区 今天下午5点
- Yes! - Alright Clacket Lane services, M25, 5pm today
你们绝对难以相信现在发生了什么!
You would not believe what's happening to me right now!
#镜中世界#
#Through the looking glass
刘易斯·卡罗尔的小说
嗨!
Hello!
我不知道该在哪儿等 克拉克肯特港那么大
I wasn't sure where to wait, Clacket Lane is pretty elaborated, isn't it?
我本来想在苏格兰银行取款处等你们
I was gonna stand by the Bank of Scotland cash line
你知道就在皇家汽车俱乐部会员店旁边
you know next to the RAC membership store there
但是嗯...我想了想还是站在入口比较显眼的好 所以我...我就过来了...
But eh... I thought I would be more visible on the approach...so I just...decide to come here...
你们好...哦...
Hello... Oh...
好了赶快进去吧
Alright scoot over!
嗨 嗨 大家好
Hi, hi, everybody.
嗨 我刚才和Don说我不知道该站在哪儿
Hi, I was just saying to Don that I didn't know where to stand cause
因为我怕你们看不见我
I thought you might not see me, so...
- 我有医生证明...  - 这边请
- I have a certificate... - This way
这个是正规医疗文件 证明 你看这是院方印章
It's an official medical documents, certificate, you know, the official stamp
这些都是合法的...
It's all legal and eh...
嗯...你觉得Frank怎么样?
So... What do you think of Frank?
- 呃... - 他真他妈赞 不是吗?
- Umm... - Fucking amazing, isn't he?
他的才能简直没有边界
He does all the way out there man, the furthest corners.
操 我真想变成他
Fuck, I wanna be Frank.
Don?
嗯?
Yeah?
- 那个头套   - 闻起来像根香肠
- The head. - Smells like sausages.
- 他从来没把它拿下来过 - 从来不?
- He never takes it off. - Never?
对 从来没拿下来过
Nah, never.
他带着这个睡觉?
He sleeps in it?
对
Yep.
那他吃饭呢?
What about eating?
他从脖子下面伸上来一个吸管吸食液体食物
He sucks liquid food to a straw that he follows up under the neck line
有时候也吸点固体 但是最好不要
Occasionally solids but it's not encouraged.
哪种液体食物?
What kind liquid food?
Grownut 一种营养补充剂
Grownut. It's like a supplement.
那他肯定有一脸大胡子
He must have a very bushy beard
未必
Not necessarily
- 他怎么刷牙? - Jon你看
- How'd he clean his teeth? - Look, Jon
你必须得习惯接受这些
You just gonna have to go with this.
好吧
Okay.
- 抱歉这只是... 只是太疯狂了 - 是的 我知道 我知道... 我明白的
- Sorry, it's just...It's pretty crazy... - Yeah, I know, I know... I understand...
我告诉你吧
Let me tell you something.
Frank 尽管有他自己的小问题 但是他毫无疑问
Frank, with all this issues, is without a doubt
是我见过的最理智的家伙了
the most one hundred percent sanest cat I've ever met.
好吧
Okay.
我就完全是另一种人了
Me on the other hand.
-你看起来很正常啊  - 是么?
- Well, you seem pretty sane to me. - Yeah?
不…其实我之前在精神病院呆过好久
But... No... I spent a lot of time in a psychiatric hospital
我被诊断有严重精神疾病
I was labeled as severely mental ill.
我原来经常干塑胶模特
I use to fuck mannequins
- 额好吧 - 这是一种病症
- Right. - It's a condition.
出发啦
Here we go.
醒醒~醒醒~早餐香喷喷~
Wakey, wakey, eggs and bakey
大家下车
Everybody out
欢迎来到Vetno!
Welcome to Vetno!
我们的新家
Our new home.
- Don? Don?  - 好吧
- Don? Don? - All right.
还不错
C'est pas mal.
- 你喜欢这儿? - 没想象中的差
- You like? －C'est pas degueu.
别急着下结论
Impulse response
- 这边 -抱歉? -Nana和Baraque
- Okay, people. - Excuse me? - Nana, Baraque
-我们要在这儿住多久? - 就住这间
- How long will we be staying here for? - Shall be housing here
啊~双层床
Ah, bunks!
- 真漂亮 Nana你睡外面 - 是的哎
- C'est joli. Mon Nana tu dort hors.  - It is.
Frank?
主卧是你的
The master bedroom for you.
已经按你的要求布置过了
Had it customized for all your requirements
正好我腿酸了 太棒了
Mes deux legs etaient bien dur. Parfait.
- 简陋了点 - 我们在这儿会非常高产的
- basic accommodation - We'll have many productive seasons here
- Clara - Don? - 这是你的房间
- And Clara - Don? - Your living quarters
这边儿能看湖的全景
Nice panoramic view of the lake here
Jon 咱俩在这后面
And Jon, you and I are just through here
- Don? - 怎么了伙计? - 抱歉 Don
- Don? - Yeah buddy? - Don, sorry
事实上我周一要回去上班
I actually told work that I will be back on Monday
- 所以我在想... - 你他妈为什么还想回去工作?
- So I was just wondering... - Why the fuck would you do that?
我以为这只是个临时的活儿
Well I thought it was just a gig, you know
所以我只带了一条裤子和一件T恤
So I only brought one pair of pants and a T-shirt
我会住在这个绿色的拖车里
This is where I'll be staying, right here in the green trailer
所以晚上的时候你需要什么东西
So if you need anything at night you know
糖 牛奶 吓怕了 过来敲门就行了
Sugar, milk, you freak out, just come and knocking
来吧 快点儿
Come on, chop chop
- 那是阿尔卑斯雪松 不错哦 - Don!
- That's Alpine cedar. Nice! - Don!
- 嗯? - 我们要在这里呆多久?
- Yeah? - How long are we staying here?
直到录完专辑 Jon
Just as long as it takes to record the album, Jon.
爱尔兰的Vetno 经历了几天被Frank称为“野外工作”的日子之后
Vetno, Ireland. After several days of what Frank calls "field work"
排练正式开始了
Rehearsals proper have began
我正在融入我的新生活
I'm settling in to my new life.
也开始逐渐了解我的乐队成员们
And gradually getting to know my fellow band members
哇哦 这个真漂亮 它叫什么?
Wow! This is beautiful. What do you call it?
从我的特雷门琴旁边滚远点!
Stay away from my fucking Theremin
在一些能预料到的初期小问题之后
A few teething problems as you would expect
- 我开始感觉到能融进这个集体了 - 嘿
- But beginning to feel like one of the gang - Hey
所以...
...我不知道为什么Frank会同意你加入乐队...
...但是我完全不相信你
你让我作呕
Jon这里没听明白 学Baraque讲话而已
噢的古特?
On dégouté?
在Vetno 有一种清晰可触的表达自我的自由
At Vetno, there is already a palpable sense of free expression
而我已经迫不及待地想要投入创造力的漩涡之中去了
And I can't wait to dive into the creative maelstrom
好的大伙儿 下一次从G小调开始 知道了吗?
Okay everybody, next time around go to G minor, okay?
1 2 3 4
One, two, three, four
他妈的是大调! 大调!
Fucking major! Major!
但是当然 我会努力赢得在乐队里的地位
But of course, I shall have to earn my place in the band
而乐队的中心 就是Frank
At the heart of it all, is Frank
该怎么形容Frank呢?
How to describe Frank?
大部分情况下 他看起来很友好
Mostly, he seems friendly.
尽管有些时候
Though sometimes
- 有点过激 - 这会是值得的!
- A little intense - It'll be worth it!
-停! -这会是值得的!
- STOP - It'll be worth it!
他可以把自己藏起来好几天
He can hide himself away for days at a time
那个头套里面到底是怎样的?
What goes on inside that head?
那个头套里...
Inside that head...
太好了!
YES!
就像个大鸟笼
It's like an aviary
你们是鸟 是石头 你是谷仓
You birds. Rock. You're corn room.
娜娜 你是母鸡
Nana, you're hen
Clara 你是猫头鹰 黑夜里的猎人 沉默的杀手
Clara, the owl, night hunter, silent killer
而这儿又有什么呢?
What have we got here?
下蛋吧 你这个小红毛鸟
Laying eggs, you little ginger bird
下蛋吧
Lay an egg
Frank说他要把我们都逼到极限
Frank says he must push us to our furthest corners
- 然后才能释放巨大的音乐潜能 - 蹲下!
- And unlock the great music that hides there - Get down there, Squat!
吸气 把蛋下出来! 把那个蛋挤出来!
Blow air in, get that egg out! Squeeze that egg out!
有时候会觉得有些难以承受
It can feel a little overwhelming at times
但是总得来说
But all in all
我很高兴参与其中
I am happy to be a part of this
就是开心
Just happy.
我不想好好的!
I don't wanna be fine!
我不想!
I don't wanna be!
别这样!
Come on!
我不想活了!
I don't wanna live!
别让他靠近湖!
Don't let him get to the lake!
他跟你说塑胶模特的事儿了?
He tell you about the mannequins?
是的
Yeah
我之前见过一次
I met one once
她叫Caroline Kuntlie
Caroline Kuntlie
我叫Frank
I'm Frank
我叫Jon
I'm Jon
他现在还...?
Does he still?
不 他现在和真的女人谈恋爱了
No. He has relationships with real women now.
但是对他来说那很难
But it's hard, you know.
他不得不说服她们躺在床上一动不动 所以 你懂的
He has to convince them to lie completely still. So, you know.
- 嘿 别告诉Don是我说的 - 不会的
- Hey, don't tell Don I said anything. - No.
他觉得那是个让人羞耻的秘密
He might think it's a shameful secret.
我说 就告诉大家一切吧
I say tell everyone everything.
为什么要掩盖事实呢
Why cover anything up? Right?
我能问你件事吗
Can I ask you something?
当然
Sure.
为什么要带着它
Why do you wear that?
你觉得这样很怪吗?
You think it's weird?
有点
Kind of.
呃 普通的脸也很怪啊 不是吗
Well, normal faces are weird too, you know.
它们这么...
The way they're...
光滑着 光滑着 光滑着
Smooth, smooth, smooth...
然后就 哇啦 你知道的 这是隆起啦那儿又是洞啦
and then blulalala, you know. All bumping and holes
我是说 眼睛长什么样来着
I mean, what are eyes likes?
它们就好像科幻电影似的 千万别让我开始讲嘴唇是什么样
Like a science fiction movie. Don't get me started on lips.
简直就跟超严重的伤口边缘似的
Like the edges of a very serious wound.
那倒是
That's true.
但你的头还是挺可怕的啊
But your head is still sort of intimidating.
其实呢 我正在里面给你一个欢迎的微笑
Well, underneath that I'm giving you a welcoming smile.
如果我大声说出自己的面部表情 你会觉得舒服点吗
Would it help if I said my facial expressions out aloud?
呃 可能吧
Well. Maybe.
欢迎的微笑
Welcoming smile.
Frank
你跟键盘手聊了一整晚?
You've been up all night talking to the keyboard player?
我可不只是个键盘手
I'm not just a keyboard player.
我也写自己的歌
I write songs too.
你自己写歌?
You write your own songs?
是啊
Em-huh.
有时间我很乐意唱给你们听
I love to play some for you sometime.
那我很有兴趣啊
I really like that.
大大的 不惧威胁性的露齿笑
Big non threatening grin.
- 开心的表情 - 那现在就唱吧 - 真好笑
- Delighted look. - Yeah, play them now. - Funny.
现在就唱
Play one now.
棒极了
Excellent.
- 呃 不是现在 - 不 不
- Hum, I'm not... not right now. I'm okay. - No, no.
- 我很乐意听你唱你的歌 - 我也是 唱吧
- I'd love to hear one of your songs. - I would too. Go on.
- 我 我不这么认为 所以别 - 求你了!
- I don't... I don't think so. Just ... - Please!
嘿伙计们 Jon他自己会创作音乐呢
Hey guys, Jon, he writes his own music.
他还打算给我们表演一下呢
He's gonna play some music for us.
- 来嘛 - Clara - 让我们听听你的歌 Jon
- Come on. -Clara. - Share your music with us Jon!
- 弹起来! - 好吧
- Play something! - Okay.
我手还没暖起来
I haven't warmed up my hands.
呃
Um...
好吧 呃
Okay, uh.
那只是个 只是个热身而已
That's just, that's a warm-up.
这次 这次好了
I've got one, I've got one this time
# 有一天 我走在街上 #
# I was walking down the street one day #
# 心里想着我爱的她 #
# Thinking about the lady I love #
# 这时候有个家伙走了过来 问我 你是做什么的 #
# When the guy comes down, and, says 'What do you do?' #
- 它还没 我还没写完它呢
- That's not... I haven't finished that one.
－这就是坨屎 就是坨屎
我 我有首摇滚风的
I... I've gotta a kinda rocky one.
# 穿着红大衣的女士 你拿着那个包在干嘛? #
# Lady in the red coat, what are you doing with that bag? #
我才刚...
I've only...
操 你知道吗 我写了那么多歌可现在连一首都他妈想不起来了
Fuck, you know you've just got so many songs and then just none of them fucking come out.
哦不 我想起来一首 想起来一首 这首是这样的 呃
Oh no, I've got one, I've got one. This one which is like... eh...
这是你的
That's yours.
- Don! - 啊... - 嘿 兄弟!
- Don! -Ahh... - Hey buddy!
天啊
Oh man.
你感觉怎样?
How are you feeling?
好些了
Better.
他需要一个脊椎按摩师
He's gonna need a chiropractor.
你不开心了?
You bumped out?
- 有点 - 为什么?
- Little bit. - Why?
我觉得自己找不到属于我的…
I don't think I will ever be able to find my...
音乐的核心 主题
Core, song-writing themes.
- 你懂吗 - 任何事物都可以写出一首歌
- You know? - You could write a song about anything.
是吗?
Yeah?
是啊
Yeah.
就像你的袜子
Hey... like your socks here.
它们就挺独特的
They are pretty original.
嘿 看看这个
Hey, look at this.
地毯上的一根线头
This little tuft in the carpet.
我想知道他按地毯的寿命算的话有多老了
I wonder how old is he in carpet years.
已经春天了吗?
Is it spring?
他是第一个醒过来的吗 还是
He is the first to wake or?
他老了吗? 他还够强壮吗?
Is he old? Is he still strong enough?
来抵御冬天的消耗?
To keep what winter wants to take.
# 独自立着的小线头 #
# Lone standing tuft #
# 对抗着你的踩踏 #
# Defies the foot #
# 你是否能依然幸运的立着 #
# Is it luck that you are still standing #
# 依然没有被压倒呢 #
# You've not been flattened too #
# 只是在微风吹拂下微微颤抖着 #
# You trembled beneath the gentle breeze #
# 就在我踩上去的时候 #
# That's displaced by my shoe #
# 独自立着的小线头 #
# Lone standing tuft #
- 抱歉 - Frank
- Sorry. - Frank.
这简直太棒了
That's amazing.
现在是受宠若惊的咧嘴笑 然后是害羞的微笑
Flattered grin, followed by bashful half smile.
你应该被大家熟知啊
People should know about you.
你应该出名的
You should be famous.
你能理解...
You understand...
我能理解什么?
I understand what?
你能理解外面会有人会喜欢我们的音乐
Understand that there are people out there that might like our music.
有时候我觉得 Clara并不在乎人们是否喜欢我们
Sometimes I think Clara, doesn't care if people like us or not.
真的?
Really?
这感觉挺怪
It's weird.
真的挺怪
It's really weird.
这是什么?
What is this?
土豆
Potato.
我是说这是什么?
And what is this?
炖菜啊
Stew.
你该回家了
You should go home.
Frank选的我 好吗? 所以这不是你能决定的
Frank picked me, okay? So that's not up to you.
你说什么?
Excuse me?
他说我是珍贵的
He said I was cherishable.
他选了我进这个乐队
And he picked me to join the band.
你只是听从指挥去弹琴的手指而已
You are fingers being told which keys to push.
- 我自己决定该怎么弹 - 只是十根
- I push my own keys. - Ten
小小的 骨头和皮肤而已
little bits of bone and skin.
我完全可以施展潜能的极限 写自己的歌
I'm perfectly capable of going to my furthest corners of composing music.
你的极限?
Your furthest corners?
我的极限
My furthest corners.
真应该有个人来扇你一巴掌 让你清醒点
Someone needs to punch you in the face.
嘴唇皱在一起 就好像在说
Lips purse together as if to say
不能再游荡了
Enough frivolity
今天我们要开始真正创作专辑了
Today we begin work on the album in earnest.
- Frank想让我们一切从零开始 - 记下颜色的编码
- Frank wants us to start everything from scratch. - Note the color codings
他创造出了一套全新的乐谱系统
He's created an entirely new music notation system.
整个宇宙就好像是小小的许多银河系
The entire universe's like tiny little galaxies
我们设计自己的乐器
We've designed our own instruments.
他还开始了一套严格的锻炼制度
He has initiated the straight regime of physical exercise.
- 幸运的是 我们有个安全词 以防训练太过激烈 - Chinchilla!
- Fortunately, we have a safe word when things get too intense. - Chinchilla!
Chinchilla!
Chinchilla.
说起来真是不可思议 Frank能在任何事中都能找到创作灵感
It's incredible. Frank finds inspiration in everything.
我觉得这个能给我灵感
I find this is inspiring.
他是怎么做到的?
How does he do this?
如果我想作为艺术家成长的话
If I'm to grow as an artist,
我必须像他一样看待一切
I must see as he sees.
我能为它写出一整张专辑...
I can make an entire album of it...
我竭尽全力想弄懂他的秘密
I dedicate myself to learning his secret.
我也不会让任何人妨碍我
And I will not let anybody get in my way,
无论他们多努力地尝试
However desperately they may try.
- 有人在KFC里考虑问题啊 - 是我 是我
- Somebody is thinking in the KFC - It's me, it's me!
继续 继续啊
Keep going. Keep going.
我更加确信 这支乐队
I am more convinced than ever that this band,
不管他们是否意识到了
whether they realize it or not
一定会成为一支伟大的乐队
could achieve greatness.
我会努力赢得自己的地位 虽然过程不会简单
And I will work to take my place and it's very hard.
我终会让他们见识一下我的能力
I will show them what I am capable of.
我一定会
I will show them.
嘿伙计 你在干嘛?
Hey man. What are you doing?
我在呃 写歌
I'm... composing a song.
# O~~~ O~~~ O~~~ #
伙计 我知道…
Yeah man, I know...
你知道什么?
What?
我知道当你想写首好歌结果却写出一堆屎是什么感觉
I know what it feels like to try to write a song and just comes out shit.
来 让我来帮帮你
Here, let me help this out.
这是我很久 很久 很久之前写过的一首小小的情歌
Here is a little love song I wrote a long, long, long time ago.
# 宁静的冬夜 #
# The stillness of the winter night #
# 冰水里的肌肤 #
# The frozen waters I see skin #
# 破碎在船夫的手中 #
# Is broken by the boatman's hold #
# 不要动 让我进来 #
# Be still and let me in #
# 让我进来 #
# Let me in #
# 不要动 #
# But stay still #
啊 看到没
Ah. See!
也是坨屎!
Shit too!
但Jon 你早晚会想
But look Jon, sooner or later, you're gonna get the feeling,
"我为什么不能成为Frank?"
why can't I be Frank?
或者"也许我终究成为不了Frank"
Or maybe I can't be Frank.
但是Jon 这里只能有一个Frank
But Jon, there can only be one Frank.
唯一一个
One.
Don 事实上
Actually Don,
我觉得咱们两个的歌都很棒
I think both our songs were excellent.
是嘛
Yeah
对吧?
Right?
走 我们出去散个步
Come on, let's go for a walk.
当我第一次看见Frank的时候我就知道他很特别
Yeah I've known Frank was special since the moment I first saw him.
有个傻叉当时正想把他的头套拽下来
This durst was trying to wrest his head off,
那家伙至少重300磅
I mean the guy must've weighted 300 pounds.
Frank吓坏了 他一个劲儿地后退
Frank was freaking out so hard, he just backed off.
在精神病院?
The mental hospital?
嗯
Hmmm.
你看过他不戴头套的样子吗?
you ever seen him without the head?
怎么可能见过
God, no!
也许他只是长得很丑?
Maybe he's facially disfigured?
所以不得不带着面具 就和象人*一样
Forced to wear a mask, like the Elephant Man.
[1980年电影]
我只知道 有次他告诉过我他来自堪萨斯州
All I know is, he told me once he's from Kansas
堪萨斯州的布拉夫市
Bluff, Kansas.
堪萨斯州布拉夫? 听上去挺偏僻的
Bluff, Kansas? Sounds dark.
奇怪吧!
Doozy!
现在...该回去工作了
Now... get back to work.
不幸的童年 还有精神疾病 我上哪儿去找这种灵感啊?
Miserable childhood, mental illness. Where do I find this kind of inspiration?
恭喜您
Congratulations,
你已经迈出了释放创造力的第一步
you've made the first step towards releasing your creativity
而这将会改变你生活的方方面面
in a way that will change every aspect of your life.
就拿剃须来说吧
Take everyday activities like shaving
Edward de Bono曾说
As Edward de Bono once said
有多少用传统湿剃刀的人会停下来想
how often does someone using the traditional wet razor stopped to consider
是不是比起在脸上移动剃须刀
Whether instead of moving the razor
也许保持剃须刀不动
it might be easier to keep the razor still
仅仅动脸会更简单
and simply move the face.
那是什么?
What is that?
我把它叫做 愚人的尖叫
I think it's called The Idiot Shriek
很好听啊
- 它充满了痛苦 - 够了
- Such pain. - Hey.
- 充满了空虚 - 够了!
- Such emptiness - Hey!
有人在敲门
什么事?
What?
Don 放松
Easy Don.
再来一次 从头开始
Start again. From the beginning.
我在耐心地微笑着
Patient smile
别再说你的表情了 真够烦的
Stop saying your facial expressions aloud. It's extremely annoying.
对不起
Sorry.
我们没时间了
We've run out of time.
我们花光了所有房租
We've spent all our rent money
房东给了我们三十天期限离开这房子
and the landlord gave us thirty-days-notice to leave.
但我们还没走...
And we didn't leave...
于是现在他们把Vetno租给一个来度假的家庭
So now they've rented Vetno to a family of holiday-makers
他们就站在那里
Who're right over there.
你为什么没有告诉我们
Why didn't you tell us?
我不想让你们失望
I didn't want to disappoint you.
我们都还没开始录歌呢
我知道
I know.
我能付钱
I can pay.
什么?
What?
我祖父过世的时候我继承了一笔钱
When my grandfather dead and I inherited money
说是给我的小金库
He said it was my nest egg.
他说我应当把它们用在刀刃上
He said I should only spend my nest egg on something really important.
我想让把这笔钱给你们用
I want you guys to have my nest egg.
噢 Jon!
Oh, Jon!
谢谢你
Thank you.
啊 红毛鸟
Oh, ginger bird.
这些钱能给我们足够的时间来录专辑
It'll buy us enough time to make the album.
你们在我们的度假屋里做什么?
你们在窃窃私语些什么?
该死 我们现在怎么对付他们?
Shit. What we do about them?
我真的很抱歉麻烦到你们
跟我来
让我们一起出去走走
再见! 谢谢你们!
谢谢你们给我的灵魂带来新的真谛
天哪这女的简直了...
Oh fucking Christ lady...
我已经很长时间没有写东西了
It's been a long time since I've written anything.
我们为了出新歌每天要工作14个小时...
We've been working on the new music for 14 hours a day for...
至今已有11个月了
...11 months now.
这段时间很艰辛
It has not been easy.
- 但自从我们来到Vetno以后 还没有一个人离开过 - 啊
- None of us has been left Vetno since we got here. - Yeah.
Frank拒绝录制专辑
Frank refuses to record the album
直到我们将每个细节都处理完美
Until we have perfected each and every detail.
- 他真冷酷无情 - 再来!
- He can be pitiless... - Again!
我的小金库比预想中消耗得更快
My nest egg has been depleted a lot more than I anticipated.
我们不得不在食物方面精打细算
We've had to start rationing the food.
此外
And on top of all this,
Clara对我的仇恨
Clara's hatred of me
一点未减 还是如此令人费解
Remains as strong and as baffling as ever.
- 全部给我还回来 - 才不 那是我的
- I want it all back. - No that's my...
我承认有时候我想要离开Vetno
I'll admit there have been times when I've considered leaving Vetno,
但我仍然在这
But I'm still here.
我十分感激你们这么多人继续同我共度这个旅程
And I'm glad when I see how many of you continue to join me on this journey.
- 你们知道 尽管我在这儿受尽磨难 - 刚拉完屎
- You know, despite all the hardships I've suffered here. - Just took a shit.
但我内心深处开始思索
Something inside me is beginning to stir.
我渐渐开始意识到
I've come to realize that this...
这是属于我的堪萨斯州布拉夫市
...is my Bluff, Kansas.
在Vetno 我找到了属于我的残酷童年
That here in Vetno, I have found my abusive childhood.
我的精神病院
My mental hospital.
- 它逼使我 - 噢天哪
- That, which pushes me... - Oh god.
- 做到我的极限 - 这真是太棒了
- To my furthest corners. - This is really good.
Frank! Frank 我...
Frank! Frank, I've...
进啊...
Get right in there.
伍兹在场上还留了500分
Woods left five hundred points in the yard...
在果岭中心
...to the center of the green.
很可能真进一个球了
Probably is a ball in there
进洞啊!
Get in the hole!
就是你了
You're the man.
啊 啊!
Oh oh!
我写了一首歌
I've written a song.
#La~ La~ La La~~ La~#
升调
It goes up.
#La~ La~ La La~~ La~#
耶
Yeah
#La~ La~ La La~~ La~~~~~~La.....#
太棒了
Amazing.
真的吗?
Really?
是啊
Yeah.
你真的这么想?
You really think so?
噢 这对我来说太有意义了 感激不尽!
Oh, that means a world to me. Thank you so much.
- 介意我试一下吗? - 请 - 那...
- Do you mind? - Oh, please. - Ok, so...
...稳稳地降调
...pure that down
现在升半个调
Now go up a half.
升一个调
Go up a whole.
- 恩... - 现在降回去 - 啊我明白了
- Mmm... - Now go back down. - Oh, I see, yeah.
真是棒极了!
That's fantastic.
嗯!
Uh ah.
听这儿
Here
对吧?
Right?
- 嗯 对 - 因为我们之前弹的时候... - 是在F调上
- Yeah, right. - Cuz when we were playing before... - That was like an F.
对 F调 你弹起F调来像个大师
F, yeah. You played F there like a chef.
恩
Yeah.
- 我们这里多停顿一会儿 - 好
- Let's make stop a bit more. - Okay.
明天终于开始录专辑了
我作的曲他们一点儿都没用上
#我他妈的都把存款给他们用了#
念一下开头
Read the portals.
Vetno录音 第一遍
Vetno tapes. Take one.
# 彗星尾 #
# Comet tails #
# 尖叫频率在无尽脉动 #
# Screeching frequencies at pulsing infinity #
# 兴奋的觉醒 #
# Awake in the high #
# 从未说在一起 完美流程 #
#Never said the collected, the process perfected#
# 银河呼啸而过 #
# The galactic sirens out #
# 在地盘下陷 线成团 #
# Down the dimensions to curl up strings inside the plate #
# 远远离开这条路 #
# Get out of the path over deep #
# 墙先生 #
# Mr. Wall #
# 远远离开这条路 #
# Get out of the path over deep #
# 后悔 远远离开这条路 #
# Regret. Get out of the path over deep #
# 他们不能来这里 超新星 #
# They will not be able to attend this place. Supernova #
# 我会告诉你 #
# I'll show #
# 远远离开这条路 #
# Get out of the path over deep #
# 向远处滚去 #
# Get out of the deep down down get out #
# 银河也滚开 #
# So do the galactic mother fucker #
# 你想要我们离开就离开 #
# We get down if you want #
戳 戳 戳
Stab it. Stab it. Stab it.
# 现在在一起的 不久就会分开 #
# Now what's together will soon come apart #
# 一切结束后 重回开始 #
# When it's all over, go back to the start #
干的漂亮!
Well done!
把他抬稳了
Hold on of him!
- 把绳子取下来 - 我不知道怎么弄
- Get the rope off! - Je sais pas comment faire!
再见了 Don
Bye Don.
你是我们最棒的键盘手
You're the best keyboard player we ever had.
也是我认识的最好的人
The best man I ever know.
Don以前是键盘手?
Don used to be the keyboard player?
最先是Don
First it was Don.
接着是Lucas
And then it was Lucas.
现在是你了
Now it's you.
你能尽快私信我么
有个要紧的消息要告诉你
@sim1sx 嗨@jonburroughs83
Jon 你他妈的在干嘛?
Jon, what the fuck you're doing?
@sim1sx:
明天就太迟了
我们在排最终名单
最迟在我们时区
的今晚要给答复
@sim1sx:
你是经纪人对吧?
这就是Don会想要的
It's what Don would want.
所以你就把我们的视频上传到网上了
So you've been posting the videos of us online.
这不是重点
That's not the point.
正是因为这些视频
Because of those clips,
我们得到了一次超级重要的演出机会
We've been offering really fucking important gig.
你一直在监视我们
You've been spying on us.
一个叫SXSW的音乐节
SXSW!
在德克萨斯 可有名了
In Texas. It's very prestigious
- 他们有新发现这个档... - 这太荒唐了
- They've got New Discoveries... - That's ridiculous.
快过来Frank 去洗洗吧
Come on Frank, let's get you cleaned up.
为什么视频底下写着23751?
Why is it say 23751 at the bottom?
那是看过视频的人数
That's the number of people who have watched the clip.
23571人对我们有兴趣?
23571 people are interested in us?
得了吧 Frank
Come on, Frank.
- 太神奇了 - 我就说我们会出名的
- It's like magic. - I told you we could be big.
你在这鬼地方想什么?
What are you thinking in this fucking place?
你到底在玩什么花样?
What game are you playing?
让Frank满脑子想的都是那些狗屁东西
Filing Frank's head with these bullshit ideas.
泡泡声太大 我听不见你说话
I can't hear you over the sound of the bubbles.
操 这他妈...
Fuck. How the fuck did...
你刚刚按了最高强度泡泡的按钮
You just press the full bubble strength button
不一会儿就又会开始咕嘟了
It's only the time. You just restarted.
离Frank远点儿
Leave Frank alone.
我知道你想让我变得像Don跟Lucas那样
I know you want me to end up like Don or Lucas.
但那不会是我的结局
But that's not gonna be my role...
- 在这后面... - 你是个平庸的小屁孩
- In this back... - You are a mediocre child
什么
Excuse me?
你就是个害群之马
You are an infection!
- 你就像Josef 你把他关起来 就像... - 你这是自己往坑里跳
- You're like Josef. You keep him locked up like... - You're buying a genuine pit
你就像Josef!
You're like Josef!
他他妈的叫什么?
What's his fucking name?
- Josef Fritzl! - 精神病!!
- Josef Fritzl! - Mental madness man!
Josef Fritzl 把女儿关在地窖二十多年 被控强奸乱伦谋杀非法监禁等等
贱人
Cunt!
哦操 哦操
Oh fucking hell! Oh fucking hell!
啊 啊 啊 天呐 啊 啊 啊 操
Ah Ah Ah God Ah Ah Ah Fuck
我他妈要憋死了!
I'm fucking dying!
我们以后会很尴尬的
This is gonna be awkward.
什么会尴尬?
What is?
我们 你懂的
Us. You know.
在一起
Together.
我们永远不会在一起的
We will never be together.
噢
Oh.
我觉得你...很恶心
I find you...disgusting.
呃...
Em...
恶心
Disgusting.
好吧 好吧
Yeah, okay.
所以你想说什么
The point?
Clara?
他长什么样子
What does he look like?
我不知道
I don't know.
呆在精神病院里感觉很糟糕吧 Clara
Was it awful in the mental hospital, Clara?
我怎么会知道
How should I know?!
我以为你有精神病
I assume you're mentally ill.
- 你这么觉得? - 额 嗯 - 哦
- You did? - Eh huh. - Oh.
要是你没有精神病的话
So why are you so against us finding a audience then
为什么不想让乐队拥有自己的听众
If it's not because you're mentally ill?
你爱上Frank了对吧
You are in love with Frank.
你爱他
You love him.
你害怕一旦别人爱上他 你就会失去他了
And you're scared that if other people love him, you'll lose him.
"总有一天我会摘下面具 让你看到真正的我...
"And one day I'll take off my glasses and you'll really see me...
...然后给我大大的吻"
...and with big kisses."
这就是我在想的
That's really all I think.
别对我的想法指手画脚
Don't presume to tell me how I think.
如果你搞砸了美国的事
If you fuck everything up in America,
我会拿刀捅死你的
I'll stab you.
就像德州巴黎一样 是不是
That's just like Paris, Texas, isn't it?
[1984年 电影]
你在找什么
What's you looking for?
找Don
Don.
嘿 Don
Hey Don.
嘿 伙计
Hey parter.
我记得你说过 这儿的沙漠是你在世界上最喜欢的地方
I remembered you saying that the desert here is your favorite place in the whole world.
仅次于圣地亚哥海洋世界
After Seaworld San Diego.
我知道你很想家 Don
I know you were homesick Don.
我知道有好几次 你都想回到这里
I know there were times, you wanted to come back here.
但为了我 你并没能回来
àBut you didn't because of me.
你现在终于回家了 Don
But you're home now, Don.
我保证 你所有的努力不会白费的
I promised those sacrifices you made won't be in vain.
Jon 最近预言了
Jon, just foretold of a night
今后有一天
Some nights from now
我们将感谢他的偷录
Would thanks to the secret camera.
万千为我们而疯狂的粉丝会聚集在一起
Legions, multitudes of already adoring fans, shall gather.
聆听我们的音乐并为之疯狂
And they shall receive our music and rapture.
噢 这是Grownut
Oh, it's Grownut.
Frank 看看这是Grownut
Frank. It's Grownut.
卧槽 槽...
...我拿错盒子了
Don 没事儿
All right Don.
反正也是和沙漠化在一起
Compete the desert with you anyway.
- 噢 Don - 去他妈的Grownut
- Oh, Don. - Fucking Grownut.
妞挺漂亮啊
Looking good
别碰我
Don't touch me
你们衣服很不错嘛
Nice costume guys!
噢 谢谢 谢谢
Oh, thank you. Thank you.
我们后天 额 在Sunshine演出
We're playing at the, uh, Sunshine, day after tomorrow
Frank!
给我们在SXSW演出倒计时:
- 你们好 - 看样子你们就是Soronprfbs乐队了吧
- Hello. - Something tells me that you guys are the Soronprfbs.
没错 就是我们
That's us.
你是Jon
You are Jon.
是的 你好
Yes. Then hi.
这里是音乐节的通行证 和一些资料
So here are the festival passes. And information pack.
Simone没读错你的名字吧
Did Simone pronounce your name right?
Jon.
- 问你乐队的名字 -我其实不知道
- No, the band's name. - Oh, um, actually I don't know.
- Clara 我们乐队的名字怎么读来着 - 问他啊
- Clara, how do we pronounce the band's name? - Ask him.
对了 你们饿吗
Listen, are you guys hungry?
- 额 有点 - 是这样的 因为我们刚好准备去吃饭
- Um, yeah. - Because we are gonna... go and get something to eat
这镇上最棒的煎饼屋
It's the best pancake house in town.
有开放麦克可以唱歌 肯定会很棒的
There's open-mic. It's gonna be awesome.
太好了！[先美音 后英音]
Awesome? Awesome.
# 我坐在Tracy的卧室里 #
# I sit in Tracy's bedroom #
# 我需要我们 Chelsy一直在聊男友 #
# And I need us and Chelsy's been talking boyfriends #
- 我宁愿吃快餐 - 你们在森林里呆了这么久
- J'aimerais manger le pouce - You guys have been in the forests so long
这里对你们来说肯定太疯狂了吧
And all this craziness has to be kind of overwhelming I guess.
没有啊 我们完全没觉得
No, we are cool that, you know, ah..hahah...
我很开心在这发行我们的新专辑 高兴的表情
...I'm delighted to be launching our album here. Delighted look, you know...
这对我们来说绝对是
This is most...
最难得
...unique...
最振奋人心的机会
...and exciting opportunity...
你给了我们一次为那些真正懂我们爱我们的人表演的机会
...you've given us to finally playing for the people who actually know and love us.
你知道吗 目前为止我们的粉丝都是偶然发现我们的
You know, until now our audience attend to be people who chanced upon us.
然后听了没几分钟就意识到他们并不喜欢我们的音乐
And realized after few minutes they don't like us.
Frank
实际上 我得告诉你们 我们当然知道你们是谁
Actually I gotta tell you guys we know who your are
毕竟是Simone和我找的你们 但观众不一定会认识你们
Simone and me we found you but the audience won't have heard you yet
他们不是已经了解我们并且喜欢我们吗
They do not know and love us?
可Youtube上可是有两万三千七百多人看过我们的视频啊
But more than 23700 people watched us on Youtube
额 两万三千点击量其实不算什么
Um, 23000 hits on Youtube means nothing.
- 他们并不是知道我们 - 现在这样
- They do not know us. - Yeah, those kind of...
也许那里会有几个知道你们的人
Maybe one or two people in the room will know you
也可能没人知道 至少得五十万的点击率才有可能开始出名
Maybe nobody. Half a million, that's when you're onto something big.
- 我们搞砸了 - 但他们更友善吧 肯定会喜欢我们对吧
- We fucked it up. - Ok, but they are cooler, right? I mean they'll like us.
他们会爱死你们的
They'll love you
Jon, Jon?
残酷的现实让乐队心生疑问
Recent revelations have raised serious questions in the band.
我们在新发现这里到底会受到什么样的待遇
About the reception we can look forward to at New Discoveries.
跪舔我呀!
Lick my ass!
我赶紧组织今晚早点排练
I hastily arranged the warm-up gig earlier this evening.
－太糟糕了
可惜没能稳定人心
Did nothing to steady this shit.
幸运的是 我不再是一年前的那个我了
Luckily, I am no longer the man I was a year ago.
危机来临时 我依然能看到转机
Now in crisis I see creative possibility.
或许我比他们意识中的我 更接近这个时代精神
Turns out I maybe closer to the Zeitgeist than certain people gave me credit for.
独立乐队独霸SXSW
我已经准备好在这个乐队大放异彩了
I am ready to make my mark on this band.
你想让我们改变风格
So you want us to change our sound?
你看 我们总是想让听众拼尽全力
Look, we always demanded the audience stretch their corners.
来迎合我们的音乐
All way out to meet ours
但是Frank 如果
But what if, Frank.
如果我们稍微收敛一点呢 就一点点
What if we pull our corners back? A little bit.
就小小一点点
Just... no just a tiny tiny bit.
这样大家都开心了
And then everyone's corners can meet you know
虽然我们还是保留着我们的风格
In the places still where in the really long way off.
但是就不那么
But it's just a bit less...
你懂吗... 更容易喜欢上的那种...
You know? And a bit more likable.
这并不坏啊
But not in a bad way
我他妈的才不弹乌克丽丽
I'm not playing the fucking Ukulele
Frank.
我正在写我最能被人喜欢上的歌
I'm writing my most likable song ever.
我总希望有一天会有一个成员
I've always dreamed that one day I'd have a band member
能够接受我的想法 作出人们超级喜欢的音乐
who shared my vision, of creating extreme likeable music.
Jon 谢谢你
So thank you, Jon.
谢谢你推我一把
You gave me the little push I needed.
好 不多说了
OK, enough chatter.
我要给你们来一首
Here it is.
我作的最能让人喜欢上的歌
My most likeable song ever.
# 可口可乐 唇膏戒指 夜夜笙歌 #
# Coca Cola lipstick ring go dance all night dance all night #
# 我最能跳舞 我最能跳舞 #
# I've got dancing legs I've got dancing legs#
# 他们舞不停 他们舞不停 #
# They won't stop dancing No They won't stop dancing #
# 吻我 吻我 娜芙蒂蒂 吻我 #
# Kiss me Just kiss me Kiss me Nefertiti #
# 如你所好 如你所好 #
# Just the way you like it Just the way you like it #
# 吻我 吻我 唇膏 吻我 皱皱的唇膏 #
# Kiss me Kiss me lipstick kiss me lipstick wrinkle #
# 就如你所好 #
# That's the way you like it #
你说的最能让人喜欢上的歌就这个吗
This is your most likeable song ever?
对呀
Ya!
大家会爱死这首歌的
People will love it.
额 额 Frank
Actually... actually, Frank.
我觉得我们还能让它更受欢迎
I think that we could push the likability even further.
怎么可能
No way.
你在耍我呢 要怎样?
You're shitting me. How?
能让我...
Can I just... um...
你刚弹到哪来着
Where did you... where did you stop?
如果我们把他 额 改的有规律一点
What if... I don't know, regulate it a bit more.
我喜欢 我喜欢
I love it! I love it!
额 如果这边用F调弹的话会不错呢 你觉得呢
And then maybe you know, um, if we play in F down here. That would be good, wouldn't it?
你真应该出名!
You should be famous!
这个太让人喜欢了!
That's so likeable!
Jon改好了这首歌哈哈哈
Jon fixed it! Oh ho haha
!!!回归正轨,迎接派对!!!
从没见过Frank这么兴奋过!
我真的在这儿了 看我证件
I'm officially here! Check me!
你好啊 哦 抱歉
Hello! Oh sorry.
我们要放手一搏大放光彩 我们要放手一搏大放光彩
We're igniting the light and letting it shine. Igniting the light and letting it shine...
嗨 恩...我能采访一下你们吗
Hey! Hi, um, can I get a quick word with you?
我们就像藏在森林里的小松鼠 没人喜欢…
We were in forests like secret squirrels, nowhere likable...
我们真是太…
We are soooo...
场面会很壮观的 Jon搞定了所有事情
It's gonna be huge. Jon fixed everything.
你们明晚一定要来看我们的演出啊
You gotta come see us tomorrow night!
- 你们一定会被我们的演出征服的! - 谢谢你
- I promise we'll be flapping you. - Thank you so much.
- 我想... - 我们出去走走吧
- I wanted... - Let's go take a walk.
我在这很开心 我很好 我一点儿都不紧张
I am incredibly happy to be here. I'm fine! I'm relaxed!
太好了
Great.
你就 原谅我之前的失礼吧
You know, forgive me for my problem formerly.
大家会喜欢我们的演出的
People will like it.
等一下
But wait!
我很好 我好着呢 我现在非常放松
I'm fine, I'm fine. I'm totally relaxed.
我很好 好得不能再好了
I'm fine. I'm perfectly fine.
Frank现在非常糟糕
Frank is not OK.
- 你在说什么呢 - 你得帮我带他离开这里
- What're you talking about? - I need your help to get him out here.
他都说了他没事啊
He said he's perfectly fine.
- 放松点 - 你得帮我带他离开这儿
- Relax. - I need your help to get him out of here.
我看他挺开心的啊
He looks happy to me.
可你看起来...
Where as... you seem...
我看起来怎么了
I seem what?
有点快崩溃了
Not in control.
Frank?
打扰一下 你有看到一个戴着头套的男人吗
Sorry, did you see the man wearing a fake head?
- 恩…戴着一个特别大的头套的? - 对
- Yeah great big head?  - Yeah.
恩…他好像…去前面那个拐角了
Yeah... He like...he went around the corner.
Frank? Frank!
Frank!
Frank?
你们他妈的在干什么
What the fuck are you doing?
没事了 没事了 没事了...
It's okay, it's okay, it's okay...
Frank你想回酒店吗
Do you wanna come back to the hotel, Frank?
那里暖和一些
It's warm there.
别听她的 她精神不正常
Don't listen to her. She is the one who's nuts.
不是你
Not you.
明天晚上是我们的一切
Tomorrow night is everything.
我们都努力了那么久了
We've work for.
他们一定会爱上我们的
They are ready to love us.
他们会爱上你的 Frank
They are ready to love you, Frank.
别浪费了这么好的机会
Don't throw that away.
Frank 别走
Frank, stay with me.
谢天谢地
Oh, thank God!
走吧
Come on.
对不起
I'm sorry.
你看起来有点沮丧啊
You're a little sad.
是啊 Jon
Yes, Jon.
我是有点沮丧
I'm a little bit sad.
哦 不
Oh, no!
Chinchilla Chinchilla
我操
FUCK
啊啊啊 她他妈的拿刀捅了我的腿
Ahhhh! She stabbed me in the fucking leg!
离我远点儿
Get off me!!
- Frank - 你他妈谁啊 - Clara Vagner
- Frank! - Who the fuck are you! - Clara Vagner
属于我们乐队的Syd Barrett今天被逮捕了
Our very own Syd Barrett was arrested today.
Syd Barrett英国歌手，作曲者，吉他弹奏家，艺术家。
作为摇滚乐手在舞台上活跃了大约十年的时间，随后由于精神问题过起了隐居的生活
并以袭击并捅伤我的腿被起诉 进了监狱
and charged with assault after stabbing me in the leg. Ceiling.
我们都会非常想念Clara的
We will all miss Clara.
并且也都真诚地希望 我们自己的才能能继续发光发热
And sincerely hope, our own crazy diamond will also shine on.
Baraque 开门
Open up! Baraque!
他在这儿吗?
Is he here?
他怎么样?
How is he?
Il dort. [意为"他在睡觉" Jon没听懂这句]
他死了吗?
He's dead?
呃 他在睡觉
Eh... asleep.
他病了
He is sick.
不 不 他只是累了 他今晚就会好了
No, no, he's just tired. He will be alright tonight.
我说的不是Frank
Not Frank.
是你
You.
你说什么?
Sorry?
我早就知道会这样
I've known this.
自从那天在海滩上我第一次见到他就知道会这样
Since the first time I saw him on that beach,
他会为了在乐队里得到一席之地而把Lucas淹死
he would've drown Lucas to take his place in the band.
你说什么呢 我才不会
No, I wouldn't have.
因为他就是那种
Cause when he looks inside himself,
内心空虚到一无所有的人
he can't find anything there.
并不是好吗
Yes, I can.
所以他只能指望着你的天赋来提升他自己
So his only hope is to live up of your talent like a tick,
你说什么啊
Sorry?
这就是为什么他必须要摆脱掉Clara
which is why he had to get rid of Clara.
是Clara自己拿刀捅了我
Clara chose to stab me.
没有Clara我们是不会演出的
We are not playing without Clara.
你胡说什么啊?
What are you talking about?
三小时之后我们将会迎来这辈子最大的演出机会
We've got the biggest gig of our lives coming up in three hours.
她捅我的时机不能更糟了 Frank
The stabbing could not have come at a better time, Frank.
我听说在SXSW的每一个人...
I've heard everyone at SXSW...
Baraque和我已经把行李收拾好了
Baraque and I have packed our things.
我们要走了
We're leaving.
不 你们不能走
No, you can't leave.
我们的视频已经有了767328次点击了啊
We've had 767328 hits!
Frank 说点儿什么啊
Frank, say something.
767918次了
767918.
他们都在看着我们
They are all watching.
有这么多人在看着我们
So many people.
看见了吧
See.
居然有这么多人在看着我们
So many people.
别走! 操…
Don't. F...
祝你在没有乐队的情况下演出成功
Good luck playing tonight without the band.
送你三个字
I've got one word for you.
不插电!
Unplugged!
我弹吉他 你来演唱 大家很喜欢不插电的乐队
Me on guitar, you on vocals. Delicate really like bands to go unplugged.
大卖点呢
Special thing.
你的腿怎么样了
How's your leg?
没什么大碍了
Oh, it will be okay.
我们照你们的要求把东西都弄好了
We set everything up, like you guys asked.
你确定要继续今晚的演出吗?
Are you sure you wanna go ahead?
哦 当然了
Oh, absolutely.
Frank你还好吗
Frank, are you okay?
还好
Uh huh.
呃 你们两个还好吗 要我肯定会很紧张
Uh, how's you guys? I'd be so nervous.
是啊 各种紧张
Oh, goes the territory.
我是说 发生了这么多之后还要在没有乐队的情况下演出
Yeah, but, I mean, playing without your band after what just happened,
天啊 要我的话得紧张死
Shit, man. I would be nervous.
不过我们还是记得我们的曲子的 所以...
Well, it's not like we don't know the songs or anything.
要有那么多人看着我 我肯定直接就崩溃了
With that many people I would be shitting myself.
你能闭嘴了吗
Would you please shut your mouth?
我只是想说我...
I'm just saying that I...
你要去哪儿
Where are you going?
让我净化一下!
Do my ablutions.
可那儿不是卫生间
That's not the toilet.
快 快点儿吧那就
Just, use quick as you can.
还有半分钟上场
Thirty second.
Frank
Frank?
Fuck啥?
What's fuck?
请在这儿稍等一下
Please wait here for a few seconds, okay?
准备狂欢吧!
Prepare for rapture!
在SXSW的大家好
Hello, SXSW!
虽然经历了疯狂的一天 我们还是来了
It has been a crazy 24-hour, but we are still here.
我们依然是Soronprfbs!
And we are still the Soronprfbs!
不插电版
Unplugged!
Chinchilla!!
这是我写的一首歌
Okay, here is a little song I wrote.
希望你们喜欢
I hope you'll like it.
这是我人生中最棒的一天
This is the best day of my life.
Frank
Frank?
Frank!
Frank 你怎么了
What is it, Frank?
Frank 来啊
Frank,come on.
你怎么了
What is it?
这歌简直就是屎
Music shit...
你的歌 简直就是一坨屎
Your music is shit.
我们不应该在SXSW演出呢吗
Aren't we supposed to be playing at SXSW?
唉 Frank
Uh, Frank.
我知道你不喜欢那首歌
I know you weren't happy with the music.
那就让我们一起想办法来修改它
So let's work on it together.
为什么不?
Why not?
因为你不是Clara
You're not Clara.
旅店老板说如果我们周末不能交齐房款
The motel owner saids if we haven't paid him full by the end of the week,
就得滚蛋了
he's throwing us out.
我擦!
Fake!
我真想毙了自己
I wanna shot myself.
- 对不起 对不起 - 操
- I'm sorry. I'm sorry. - Fuck.
他妈的别管它了
Fucking leave it.
啊 你臭死了
Oh, you stink!
我为你做的
I made it.
你就不能用用吗
Now will you use it?
把它摘了
Take it off.
把头套摘了
The head.
也许你就应该摘了它
Maybe you should take it off.
在认知行为治疗中他们说
In cognitive behavioral therapy they say,
要直面你的恐惧
Face your fears
他们会说
They say
摘了那头套
Take the head off.
所以你要摘了它
So let's do it.
赶紧把那该死的头套取下来
Let's take the fucking head off.
我有医生证明
I have a certificate.
我知道你有医生证明
I know you have certificate.
我知道你有那操蛋的狗屁证明 啊啊啊啊
I know you've got a motherfucking certificate!!! Ahhhh!
把它摘了
Take it off!
把它摘了!!!!
把头套摘下来!!!!
Take your head off!
Frank!
Frank 别走啊 Frank
Frank, no, Frank!
我知道错了
I'm sorry.
回来吧
Come back!
他去哪儿了
Where did he go?
那边
That way.
他受伤了吗
Was he injured?
他刚刚是一瘸一拐的
He was limping.
你看到他长什么样了吗
Did you see his face?
你好 你想登记走失人员吗
Yeah, hello, you want to report a missing person?
- 是的 -他叫什么
- Yes. - The name?
Frank.
姓什么
Frank what?
我只知道 叫Frank
Just Frank.
他的年龄
Age?
大概三十到五十岁之间
Somewhere between thirty and fifty?
他长什么样
And, what does this person look like?
想了半天 终于想起来你是谁了
Driving me crazy, but I know who you are.
嗯?
Eh?
你是那个总喊着Chinchilla的人 是吧
You are the Chinchilla guy, right?
是啊
Uh-huh.
牛逼
Awesome!
你们乐队里还有个带着大头套的家伙和一个疯疯癫癫的妞
And then what, there's the dude with the big head and crazy chick
叫Clara 是吧
Clara, right?
哥们 你们完全火了啊
Dude, you guys are like total mats!
我是说 网上到处都是你们的视频
I mean, there are fuckin' footage of you everywhere online.
那个Chinchilla的人 那个Chinchilla的人啊
是Chinchilla的那个人
Chinchilla guy!
是的就是他!
Aye Chinchilla guy!
看见没
You see?
我是说 那些视频太奇葩了...
I mean, all the footage are all totally erratic and shit...
什么紧张到崩溃啊 然后大喊Chinchilla!
Nervous breakdown... Chinchilla!
大家在地上滚来滚去之类的啊
People rolling around on the floor, I mean...
都是出人意料的东西诶
Just wayward stuff, man.
现在大家都在问 Frank怎么了
And now it's all like what happened to Frank?
他就像消失了一样 我是说...
It's like he just vanished. I mean...
他太他妈搞笑了
Fucking hilarious.
我不觉得哪里好笑了
I don't think it's hilarious.
是吗?
Really?
我以为你们故意表演的搞笑呢
I thought it was supposed to be hilarious.
- 那是... - 但是 Clara和Frank他们... 得了吧 他们完全就是...
- It's... - But I mean, Clara and Frank, man... Come on, they are like...
怪胎啊
total freaks.
# 独自一人吸着烟 #
# One time alone smoking #
# 被白雪覆盖 #
# I'll cover with snow #
# 于爱人遗忘时间 #
# I lost time for lover #
# 回旋太慢 #
# I cording too slow #
你怎么找到我们的
How did you find us?
我看见了这个…
I saw...
每日驻唱
你说的都是对的 Nana
Everything you said was true, Nana.
是我搞砸了一切
I ruined everything.
我很抱歉
I'm sorry.
非常抱歉
So sorry.
Frank逃走了
Frank ran away.
我...我不知道是否...
Just...I don't know if...
我觉得你们可能知道他在哪儿
I was hoping that you might know where he is.
亲爱的推特
你们有谁知道
Frank在哪里?
#寻找frank#
@buttjunkie: 我找到他了 他在我屁眼里
有奖么
@roseyd78: 爱你们 请快来西岸表演
@floppydag: 你们光说不做啊 在社交网络宣传够多的了吧
#别闹了演出啊#
@skaylktrk: 周界公路27号路口7公里的农场
告诉他们是我让你过来的 他们人都很好 #寻找frank#
这儿没人戴着假头套
Ain't nobody here wears no fake head.
好吧
Okay.
@porkalin: 你好Jon! 我是在伏尔加地区很友好的一个姑娘
@roozstah: 我应该能帮上忙
私信我
谢谢 @roozstah
希望你不是在耍我, 地点?
@roozstah 这里
堪萨斯州 布拉夫市
Bluff, Kansas.
当心!
Be careful!
嗨
Hi
Frank?
Frank 太对不起了
Frank, I'm so ashamed.
我永远都不应该逼你摘下头套的
I should never try to pull your head off.
- 我不知道... - 我只是来修树的
- I don't know... - I'm the tree surgeon.
我只是 我只是在这儿看下树
I'm just, I'm just here to look at the tree.
需要帮忙吗
Can I help you?
我很担心你
I'm very worried about you.
我只想找到你…
I just wanted to find you to...
想知道你是不是没事
make sure you are ok.
不戴头套感觉如何
How are things without the head?
他长得多么漂亮
He has such a beautiful face.
皮肤也好
Lovely skin.
那个头套都是我的错
That head was my fault.
我给他做了第一个
I made him his first one.
他才14岁
He was 14,
说是为了一个化妆舞会
said it was for a costume party.
我给他做了头套
I did it,
即使我知道根本就没什么化妆舞会
even though I knew that there wasn't any costume party.
因为对于他来说 最糟糕的事就是捅破这个谎言
Turns out the worst thing to do with something like that is to pant him to it.
世事难料啊
Who knew.
Frank到底经历了什么
What happened to Frank?
一定发生了什么事才让他变成这样的
Something must have happened to him to make him like that.
什么事都没发生
Nothing happened to him.
他得了精神疾病
He's got a mental illness.
他必定是经历的痛苦与折磨
The torment he went through,
才能创作出这么伟大的音乐
to make the great music.
痛苦并不能创造音乐
Torment didn't make the music.
音乐随处都在 硬要说的话 精神病只是拖了他的后腿
There is always musical. If anything, it slowed him down.
这是个温馨的家
Was a good home...
它就像我的家
It's just like my home.
我得走了 Frank
I have to go now, Frank.
你还好吗
You alright?
嗯
Yeah.
我知道我搞砸了一切
I know I ruined everything.
我很抱歉
I'm sorry.
看你仍然在创作真好
It's good you're still playing.
我没有
I'm not.
我试过了 但是...
I tried, but...
写不出好的音乐了
doesn't come out good.
# 我想嫁给一个灯塔管理员 #
# I want to marry a lighthouse keeper #
# 一直伴他左右 #
# And keep him company #
# 我想嫁给一个灯塔管理员 #
# I want to marry a lighthouse keeper #
# 在海边生活 #
# And live by the side of the sea #
# 我会在岛中央举办晚会 #
# And I'll have parties in the middle of the isle #
# 并做出 #
# And then makes #
# 一个珊瑚 #
# A coral reef #
# 我会邀请所有人来参加 #
# Will invite everybody in #
# 海鸥给我们伴唱 #
# And seagulls buys us score #
# 我想嫁给一个灯塔管理员 #
# I want to marry a lighthouse keeper #
# 我会在白天擦亮他的台灯 #
# I'll polish his lamps by the light of day #
# 我想嫁给一个灯塔管理员 #
# I want to marry a lighthouse keeper #
见到你们真的 真的很高兴
It's really nice, nice to see you.
能到这儿来真好
It's nice to be here.
El Madrid [酒吧名]
我爱你们这儿的墙
I love your wall.
洗手间味道有些大
Washroom smell.
该打扫了
It could be cleaner.
请抱住我
Put your arms around me
颤动的手指
Fiddly digits,
发痒的裤子
itchy britches.
# 难闻的啤酒 臃肿的人群 弥漫的烟雾 牛仔们 #
# Stale beer, fat folks, smoked out, cowpoke#
# 穿亮片的山林女人 #
# Sequin mountain ladies #
# 我爱你们这儿的墙壁 #
# I love your wall #
# 请抱住我 #
# Put your arms around me #
# 颤动的手指 发痒的裤子 #
# Fiddly digits, itchy britches #
# 我爱你们 #
# I love you all #
# 洗手间太难闻了 该打扫了 #
# Washroom smell, they could be cleaner #
# 香烟难闻的气味和小便的臭味 #
# stench of cigarettes and stale urea #
# 我爱你们 #
# I love you all #
# 浪子想要回头 #
# Prodigal son wants to return #
# 回到那个一起玩耍的地方 #
# to where the dogs played pool #
# 我爱你们 #
# I love you all #
# 难闻的啤酒 臃肿的人群 牛仔们 弥漫的烟雾 #
# Stale beer, fat folks, cowpoke, smoked out #
# 穿亮片的山林女人 #
# Sequin mountain ladies #
# 我爱你们 #
# I love you all #
# 请抱住我 #
# Put your arms around me #
# 颤动的手指 发痒的裤子 #
# Fiddly digits, itchy britches #
# 我爱你们 #
# I love you all #
【两个人的字幕组】听译出品
听译: 圭声 L.Ling Susie 朝歌 轩轩 長安君 rhico
笔译: 虹哥 長安君 陈低 小妖 Harry Joel rhico
校对: rhico 二骚 長安君 锦年
时间轴: 圭声 rhico
压制: rhico
# 在El Madrid酒吧见到你们真好 #
# El Madrid, it's nice to see ya #
# 在这里真好 #
# It's really nice to be here #
# 我喜欢你们的墙 #
# I love your wall #
# 难闻的啤酒 臃肿的人群 弥漫的烟雾 牛仔们 #
# Stale beer, fat folks, smoked out, cowpoke #
# 穿亮片的山林女人 #
# Sequin mountain ladies #
# 我爱你们 #
# I love you all #
# 请抱住我 #
# Put your arms around me #
# 颤动的手指 发痒的裤子 #
# Fiddly digits, itchy britches #
# 我爱你们 #
# I love you all #
# 洗手间太难闻了 该打扫了 #
# Washroom smells they could be cleaner #
# 香烟难闻的气味和小便的臭味 #
# stench of cigarettes and stale urea #
# 我爱你们 #
# I love you all #
# 浪子等着回头 #
# Prodigal son waits to return #
# 回到那个一起玩耍的地方 #
# to where the dogs played pool #
# 我爱你们 #
# I love you all #
因为有的他围观者的精神和大大的假脑袋才有了此作
谨以此部电影献给Chris Sievey
# 破碎的 #
# Banjaxed and broken #
# 碎成一片片的 #
# Smashed up in bits #
# 只有这样所有的东西才能合在一起 #
# That is the only way everything fits #
# 捏在一起 #
# All held together #
# 用着口水团成球和线 #
# Spitballs and strings #
# 树上的尖头戳着鸟儿破裂的翅膀 #
# Splinters of wood on bird's broken wing #
# 现在在一起的 不久就会分开 #
# Now what's together will soon come apart #
# 一切结束后 重回开始 #
# When it's allover go back to the start #
# 现在在一起的 不久就会分开 #
# Now what's together will soon come apart #
# 一切结束后 重回开始 #
# When it's allover go back to the start #
# 地毯上独自立着的小线头 #
# Lonely little carpet tuft #
# 你刚刚扯下来的小线团 #
# A twisted wool you just retreat #
# 被倒下的同伴围绕 #
# Surrounded by its fallen friend #
# 独自在这陈旧的地毯上 #
# Alone in threadbare woven field #
# 独自立着的小线头 #
# Lone standing tuft #
# 对抗着我的踩踏 #
# Defy the foot #
# 按地毯年龄算你有多少岁了 #
# What age are you in carpet years #
# 已经春天了么 你是第一个苏醒的么＃
# Is it spring and you are the first to wake #
# 或许虽然你已年长 但依然能抵抗寒冬 #
# Or are you old but still strong enough to keep what winter wants to take #
# 独自立着的小线头 #
# Lone standing tuft #
# 对抗着我的踩踏 #
# Defy the foot #
# 你是否能依然幸运的立着 依然没有被压倒呢 #
# Is it luck that you are still standing and you've not been flattened too #
# 在我踩上去的时候 也只是在微风吹拂下微微颤抖着 #
# Do you tremble in the little wind that squeezed out by my shoe #
# 独自立着的小线头 #
# Lone standing tuft #
# 对抗着我的踩踏 #
# Defy the foot #
# 你小线头强大的精神 是不是钢铁造的 #
# As you tuftiness mutated soul your strands are made of steel #
# 是单单毅力就能让你免于被压倒在鞋跟之下么 #
# Is it sheer determination you've never been beneath the heel #
# 独自立着的小线头 #
# Lone standing tuft #
# 对抗着我的踩踏 #
# Defy the foot #